Cutie and the Boxer is a documentary film directed by Zachary Heinzerling.
This candid New York love story explores the chaotic 40-year marriage of
famed boxing painter Ushio Shinohara and his wife, Noriko.
Anxious to shed her role as her overbearing husband's
assistant, Noriko finds an identity of her own.
Self, played by Noriko Shinohara.
Self, played by Ushio Shinohara.
Cutie and the Boxer is a 2013 American documentary film
produced, shot, and directed by Zachary Heinzerling.
The film focuses on the chaotic 40-year marriage of two artists, Noriko Shinohara and her
husband the boxing painter Ushio, featuring original artwork by the couple.
Heinzerling said of the couple:  "When I first met [the Shinoharas], I was just struck by the raw spirit and beauty that
emanates from their faces, their lifestyle, their art, everything about them has so much purpose and character.
Even if you don’t speak Japanese, even if you have no previous knowledge of their
artwork or who they are, you’re immediately captivated by their presence.
They live in a world that’s kind of a time warp that hearkens back to the ‘70s New York SoHo art
scene that is sort of canonized in history, certainly from my point of view."
The film explores themes of artist, painter, art, elderly.